ALEKSEY POTAPOV

Senior IOS Developer

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Kohutova 10, 821 08, Bratislava Slovakia

PHONE

+421949474199

EMAIL

ing.aleksey.potapov@gmail.com

SKILLS

iOS Development: since 2012

Objective-C: 8+ years of professional experience

Swift: 6 years of professional experience

Familiar with Java and Kotlin for Android development

Scripting Languages: Python, Bash, Ruby

Git and Gitflow for version control

Agile Scrum and Kanban workflows

Mostly used: Apple CarPlay, Core Location, Core Bluetooth, RxSwift, MVVM approach, Unit Testing, Dependency Injection

Familiar with: SwiftUI, Combine

LANGUAGES

Russian, Ukrainian (Native)

English (C1 level)

Slovak (B2 level), Czech (A2 level)

German (A2 level)

PROFILE

I am iOS Developer with 7+ years of professional experience. I focus on result along with the code quality. I do mentoring for colleagues and perform internal workshops. I love simplicity and clean design in apps. While developing an app, I follow Apple Human Interface Guidelines to bring more benefits to users.

More info on my personal website: https://alekseypotapov.dev

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

iOS Developer, Sygic a.s.

Bratislava, Slovakia

Aug 2017 — Present

Sygic GPS Navigation app

My role: implement new features using Sygic SDK, RxSwift and MVVM architecture

Onlia Sense app

My role: app implementation from scratch till shipping using Swift, Firebase, Twilio

iOS Developer, Alice in Tokyo

Bratislava, Slovakia

Mar 2015 — Jul 2017

Internet of Things projects

My role: implement connection to smart devices on local network using Objective-C, Swift, ReactiveCocoa, Typhoon for Dependency Injection, Swift Protocol-Oriented Programming

iOS Developer, Mobindustry Corp.

Dnipro, Ukraine

Jun 2013 — Aug 2014

Outsourcing various projects using Core Location, iOS camera, custom UI elements

EDUCATION

Master's Degree of Applied Informatics, Slovak University of Technology in Bratislava

Bratislava, Slovakia

Sep 2014 — Jun 2016

Bachelor of Computer Science, National Mining University

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine

Sep 2010 — Jun 2014